So, when
Tim and I were planning this retreat, we were
thinking about which classes we should hold,
and it is bad
luck in
Buddhism not to complete a teaching
, to complete a class
.  The last Lamrim took 12
years to develop, but we
finished it.  So let's
applaud ourselves.  And there is another
important class.  That means Dzin
Chang
says.
Changsen
means the tendency to think that the
ship comes from the pen
.  Hold on to a pen that
was made in a factory, not by
you.  Do you understand what I mean?  If
you believe that the pen
was made in a factory, then you have
this mental illness
called skepticism, and everyone has this mental
illness.  Even if you teach the pen
, you still have this disease.  That's
somewhat
funny, but it's very, very old and
it's inside you.  Shame
means to distinguish between two people
.  In America we have something
special.  Sometimes you can
see it if you observe it.  It's
called Road Rage and it's where
the drivers touch each other by
chance.  They talk to each other and then they start
to
argue.  This happened to a friend of mine
.  He lives in Rim, is not
Sender, and
someone stole out of the car dealership
and showed him a hairstyle,
and then he said no, that's
all okay, nothing happened.  So
this is one way you can
meet someone.  That means Changdem.
In Tibetan it is called
Changdem.  Like a fight.  like a fight
.  So, in this book, it's a
long book of poems.  It is called the
battle between the good part of your
mind and the bad part of your
mind.  And it's a bitter fight.
It's really like a street fight.
And my teacher introduced it to me
many years ago, I
think
probably 35 or 40 years ago
now.  And he
taught it to us, and it's very long, and he
couldn't finish it.  He
died before he could finish it,
and that's kind of bad luck,
not being able to
finish something.  So I thought I'd like to
teach it and I'd like to
finish the translation.  And then it felt like
we had
finished it.  It's a truly
great book.  It's a battle within
your own mind.  Your own mind
is divided into two parts,
the good side and the bad side, the
devils and the angels, and they
fight each other.  And it's
incredible entertainment.  And it's
a conversation we
have all the time, and ah, this person has
really hurt me.  And then you say,
no, remember the pen.  Yes, I
know the pen, but this person is
different.  No, we all say that.  every
day.  We'll say it 100 times.  Every day.
Every day.  And I'm sitting outside in
my house and it's relatively cold.  What
's the coolest thing you
can do in that moment?
You
can, um, in Kyoto all toilets are
heated.  They have
electronic heated toilet seats.
I thought I was in paradise, and
then I came back to your Marius, to
my Retus, and it was so
cold.  I got up and
thought, oh, I can't
imagine sitting down there again,
but then I sat down again
.  But then I argued in my own
mind.  My own
mind argued with my own mind,
and this is truly a
beautiful book.  How many
years ago did we start there, inam?
We started this about 14 years ago
and we are still working
on this book and I don't have much
time to teach it, but I want to, I
will not give up on
teaching it.  And if you follow the Diamond Way
, if you are a Diamond Way person
,
perhaps the brother has sent you this
book this time.  Maybe, just maybe,
you can't
say yes, of course, but you
also can't say no, certainly.
It is possible that your
Diamond Way is located with
this book, that this book is meant to
help you on your Diamond
Way.  I did it this way
.  I'm
not finished yet.  It will take
approximately another three to four years, and I
want to finish it. It has
never been translated correctly, and I
really want it out in the world.  I
want people to know who is
using it.  And for me, if I
teach it, I can understand it better too
.  When I explain something differently to someone else
, I understand
it better.  If you are a teacher
, if you want to teach well, then
try
it out on your sister or your son
.  How old is your son?  19. Wow.
So, he will be a DCI teacher next year
.  Oh, okay.  Let's
continue.  I
think Bud sent you this book
and you should finish it with me.
You have to finish this with me.  You
can end it with me.  That's why
we're here at the
diamond course.  It is primarily
an
argument, a line of
reasoning, concerning the meaning
of emptiness.  And the thing about this book
is that it's funny and it was
written to be fun.  And
sometimes you laugh even if you do
n't understand what's being said.
Nevertheless, you let it happen, and it's really
funny, and it's very, very true.  It
really is also a form of
self-criticism.
This is what half of
Grandfather's mind is thinking.  For example, if I
sit down in this particular seat, here is the person who
complains, who says, this part
says, why is it so
cold?  Why isn't it warm in the morning
when you do your business?  And
why might it be at
a different temperature later on?  That
makes no sense.
You are confining yourself in your own mind,
thinking, and in this
case, that's called the devil, the bad guy.  Tim and
I worked very hard on this text
because you heard about the idea of ​​the Fäuser
and what happened
with
ACI?
I think this is one of the oldest
organizations we have.  It was
founded in 1993.
So, it's been 43
years now, 42 years, and it has grown and
grown and grown, and YSI
emerged from it, and DSCI
emerged from it, and the other organizations also grew out of it
.
CI has now been around for almost 40 years
and it has really grown big
.  If
you take the 18
basic courses, it will
take 6 to 7
years, then you take the advanced courses
and those should also take 6 to 7 years
.  That's 14 years, then you have to
do all the meditations.  That
's more, that's another 5 years,
so it's already 19 years.  Then there are
also the
retreats.  It seems like
you could actually finish before
you die.  It's too much.  It seems like too
much.  So, what we thought
happened was...  We, um,
we really want you to
become teachers.
So, if
you come here
to cook yourself in the desert in these classes, then
you can probably be a teacher
, because being a good teacher is very
similar to cooking yourself in Di
Moen.  And we thought, the
person Diamantwick is coming, you
will be a great teacher and that
is my dream.  That's in my
dream.  That's what I'm working on this year
.  And what we thought was, there are
so many things we can learn.
You can't study for 40 years
and then be a teacher, because you'll have
no hair left after 40
years, like John and I.
So my idea is that you can
specialize.  It's also the same
when you go to
university,
you don't get a BA in science
and then an MBA in
another field.  You don't do
six MBAs at Columbia University,
you don't.  So our idea is
, you can start to
specialize.  You are welcome
to come to all classes, but maybe look
into your heart.
And there are five
choices.  There are five
special features.  You can get your Bachelor's degree
or your PhD and you can start
teaching in one of these five houses.
Princons, you have to join a house
and you are very loyal to
your house, you receive
support and have fun,
you study and you
graduate together in this house.  So we
wanted to make five houses, what
are the options?  What was
the first rule?  If you,
as a teacher, don't remember something, then
ask the question: Do you remember
the first house?
Exactly, the classic house.  You
can do it this way, you can take the traditional
ACI route, you can study ID classics
, study them well
and complete 18 + 18 courses.
You can, it is, it is the reason, it is
the basis of the
course.  Your first 18 basic courses
from ACNI, then you will have studied the most important
content of the history course.
Incidentally, they sit there for 12 hours
every day,
constantly.  You, um, sometimes do
n't even know if it's a class.  You go
to the classroom and it's empty and they
say, "Am I in the right place?"  No, I
wasn't
told at all that they don't study like at
Western universities.  The
system is pretty crazy.  Okay, let's
continue.
Some people like it, like
Word, some are nerds, they want to
study philosophy.  That's just how I am; I
go to
philosophy classes and talk about it.  I
think that if I
achieve Buddhaft, then it will be the
philosophical part
.  Some people also prefer
the Martihaus,
which is meditation.  Some people
really love meditation.
To study this book.  Hey, here's
another
book.  The last 35 books weren't
enough.  Hey, read this book.  Oh, can't
I just
meditate for a bit in between?  I don't want to
read books all day.  Other people, there are those who
like meditation
and who have friends with them.  And her
dream is to be a meditation teacher,
not a Tibetan
teacher.  And
we have, we should have a house like
this.  We should
have a degree like this.
The
joy of joining this house may be the
meditation house.  You might
not have to look like the person
in this picture when you reach graduation,
but really great
meditators don't show it like that
.  John Brady is, I believe, the
best meditator I
know, and he doesn't look it.
The beard is a little
different.  I
mean, it's a quiet
thing and you don't look like anything.
You could also look like a businesswoman
.  You could look like an
import or
export manager, for example from
Vietnam, who is also a great
meditator.
It depends on you if you
feel more compelled to meditate.
If you close your eyes and
think about your future, and then you think, "
I am a group of people doing empty meditation
," then you are
welcome to join the Sommus
.  It doesn't mean you do
n't listen to philosophy classes,
it means you specialize in them
.
If I decide what I am, it's what
I tell people on the
plane.  You're sitting next to
someone on a plane, and then they start
talking, and
then you say to that person,
"Hey, I'm an
initiation teacher, and if you say, '
Hey, I want to be a Gesche, do you
understand?' Then join the other
house
. The classic
house, the third
house. What do you call it?
The Mountain
House. I really like retreats,
and there are some
people who
are really hungry to
do more retreats. Hey, I have a
new book for you, and I'll teach you
a new meditation. Oh, I'm sorry,
I'm very
busy. Oh, I'm sitting in
my
retreat cabin right now. I can't
read a book." They, whose thing is being on
a mountain, meditating,
being in a deep retreat, they only see us again every six years,
like Lama Palma.
So, if you're that kind of person
whose dreams are big, of those
great people who
are in retreat for a long time and warm, then join
that house.  Well
. I'm
not entirely
sure which house interests me
. But I think if you can
get five people into a house and
start there, that's enough. I'm
not interested if there are 100 people
in the classic house or only two
people in the Ret house. I do
n't care. I want you to be
where you are. So,
what's the fourth one? Yes,
the Staircase House. Yes, L. Exactly, the
Lam. I call it
Lamrim anyway. As you've seen over the past 12
years, it's a big
subject. We've covered one Lamrim
. I
came across hundreds of Lamrims on John's data trail
. You can spend an Eastern life
studying
and reading Lamrims. There are many, many
beautiful ones. What we just
finished took 12 years,
and doing two of them would
take 24 years. You could become a master at it
. Maybe that's
what you
want. But I think everyone wants to
be in the fifth house, too. Is it the
Diamond House, the
Diamond Way House? Because everyone
wants to be in the Diamond House, we wo
n't allow you to be in the Diamond House, because
then you'll be ignoring the other four
houses. So we have a plan.
Uncle Tim and I have a plan.
Enter one of the four houses. You did
n't have to decide today.
You don't have to sign
your life contract in blood
. Go into what you
find attractive. I'm going to tell you something
very profound. My teacher's advice, regarding
all five
subjects, was, choose what you truly
have. And which one is it? It's the 13th
course. Why is it just a lucky number?
I don't like logic. And then
he said, "Okay, you want to master this subject of logic
." His advice was: Enter the house
you don't like, because that's what
you haven't perfected yet
. If you master something
you have no interest in, then
you won't be interested in it, you'll be a
master of both
. For example, learn to retreat to  Do something
or study philosophy. That's
an option, right? I'm
not forcing you if you've always dreamed of being
in a
cabin—er, out in the wilderness. What do
we call it again? A
mountain cabin. Whatever you like, you're
free. You're very
free. But what we're asking this
week is that we want you to make
a pre-selection,
a choice. I told you the
story about my wife,
which you'll obviously never tell.
I went out with
her to
buy her some jeans in a store where there's
no seat for the man to sit.
And he tried on over 30 pairs of jeans
. How many did she buy?
Not a
single one. So, what does it mean? Try
different cabins. Try on
different cabins. See if
they fit. You're not forced
to choose one or the other. One or the
other might not fit as well
. What's the biggest thing I've
ever done on a tour? Sy
knows
. I was brave and
bought a pair of pants and  It fit.
If you write a story about my life
, it'll start with "
Ah," and he also brought his wife trousers that
fit
. So the house is like the one in
Harry Potter,
for example. How do you decide which house
you're in? How do you decide
which house you're in? What's it called
?
Sound there. Now he's back again. Exactly.
We get this hat. In Harry Potter,
you put on this hat
and it tells you: "Hey, you should
be in the Meditation House, but we do
n't have this hat."  So you have to
decide for yourself.  Where?  Why can't Harry Potter
decide for himself?  Which
house would be good for Harry
Potter?  So this week's game
is whatever Tim says.  You choose a
house that you like, where you would like to
be
, which also means you would
like to be a teacher of what you would
mainly like to teach other people.  And then you focus from that
.  It helps you
focus on whatever you
choose, whatever your degree is going to be
.  We help you
focus on it and we create special
courses for you.
So we design special courses there to
train you to be a great teacher for your home.
And if you meet certain requirements in the
house, then you will receive
permission to enter the Diamond House.
So, by
choosing and mastering the first four houses, you have
the opportunity to enter the Diamond House
.  The Diamond House is a
kind of super house for the person who has
done well in the four houses, and
then you become a teacher in it.  So
think about what you would like to
teach?   Think
about what you want.  One of the
most important Diamond Way teachings is to
imagine what you will be like when you are
a Buddha.  This is one of the most
important
Diamond Way meditations to
introduce to you.  What would you like to look like?
John and I will be full like a
lion and
we
[music]
will so one of the
Diamond Way exercises
is to
visualize yourself as you want to be and
sometimes you can do that.  We'll talk about it
.
So the fun we're going to have
, I call it the Angel
Devil Book, the fun we're going to have
.  You will
help me make a Flowdog for this
book.  What does that mean?  It's something
I use.  I'm taking the book from
this lovely class we
had.  I've put it in the book here;
I have it on my
computer, I've opened a section,
and I've inserted a picture there
.  I was talking about the pictures
.  So, as for what I did for tight
devils, I don't have any
pictures at all.  Why?
You will create the images,
and each
house will
create images, to teach this part of the book in your own
way.  So, today I will
teach you one of the next versions of
angels and devils.
It's about the fact that the devil
is, um, quite a jerk,
quite an evil man, and he is
[music]
quite, he is really very
disrespectful.  That's what he does.
And
Tim will
guide you through every house.  You will
assemble and design the
Edems.  They design the images to
teach them.  Then we will
have special classes.  We will split into four
parts.  Every
house says, this is our image for our
first verse. This is the
way we teach the first verse for the
perspective of my house, which is the best
house.  You must be very loyal to
your house.  We have a Harry
Potter expert here.  I think he
read all the books in three days.  He
even read while he walked around.   There
are even snakes here.
You can't
do that here.
And
so I made a contract
for the platform that
offered photos for many, many
years.  I
searched online.  Is the sound quality bad right now?   Suddenly,
AI has arrived.
It was bad at first, but now AI is getting
better, and so are
books.  Now you can create an image
.  Food is called Prompt and you
write a sentence in it.  A woman
putting her spaghetti on the head of another person who is
meditating.  And you write that, and then
AI creates the image, and sometimes
they even put five
fingers on the image.  I really like it
and I use it a
lot, and maybe in your future
you'll use
AI-generated videos too, but at my age it's
pretty cool.  So, you're using
AI, you're taking a
picture and it's a great
[music]
teaching tool.  It really is a form of entertainment
.  You show
pictures and the audience, and it
's
also good to
quiz your students.  What does
this image mean?  The image should
have power.  It should be a truly
powerful image that
tells a story.  And then it's much, much
easier
to remember philosophy from an
image.
So, we can tell a story with
pictures
.  So, this time I wo
n't look for the pictures.  I would like to
have four pictures for each major teaching
I will give you, and then
you can see what your house can do
.  Tim and I will decide
who is the best, and then you'll get
a golden hat or something like that
.
No, that's too
American, but we'll have fun
.  There was a well-known person from
Mexico who had a new show
.  We did that a very long time ago
.  We had a
contact, a competition for Idams
here.  How many years ago?  Ten
years ago, right?  And he did his best
.  He won the prize and
it was great.  It was truly
great.  I think he did a really
great job that day.
But he just got back from Kyoto
and he's learned something too, so we
should give him a round of applause.
He and
Adam gave a great course,
namely a
Kyoto course.  Many thanks to our Japanese
friends.
They are really friendly, and also a
little wild.  Adam and he
gave a great class and they were
also
given a task by Nick and
Tim to go there and give that class
and it was very enjoyable for them.
Unfortunately, they are on their way back,
but they flew over Hawaii earlier
.  Ah, I also lived in Hawaii
for 6 months
.  Which of these beaches did
you visit and simply marvel at
?
Both of
them are in Oaha, that's where you can find the
bikinis.  In Nor is there to
open, you understand,
R?  I obviously don't know which
beach you were at.
So, if you want to do something like that,
you can talk to Tim and Nick
.  And they definitely went
to Kyoto and had
a really great time.  They have helped many
people
.  Anyone can do this.  It's
called Jbox.  I will talk about it one day
.  Okay, let's continue.  I
will now teach angels and devils,
and while I speak,
think about what image you will create with
the AI,
and it will help you become a
better teacher.  Your
teaching career will benefit; your
pictures help people
remember things.
And my opinion
is that everyone in this class or
everyone
online, you can learn to be a teacher
, because it is a
responsibility to teach this to others.
Everyone is
different.  Adam is not
here today.  Let me tell you something.  His
first class.  Can I show you his first
class?
It was about 12 years ago.  It
was a phoenix and I taught them
what to say and he
stood up and he left, it was something like
that.
Adam,
Adam, sit down now and he says, "Okay,
we'll work on it."
He is completely frozen.  The first
time I used my first cup, I
also froze.  My teacher
told me to sit down and shut up
.  So, you're learning.  You can
learn, you will learn.  And in my
opinion
, everyone who is listening, everyone who is listening right now
, can be a teacher and should
be a teacher.  And in the tradition
of the ancient
wisdom texts, you are not
allowed to take a class if you do
not want to become a teacher.  If you do
n't intend to share it with someone
, then you shouldn't be
sitting here on it, considering the rules of the
past
.  Sometimes, sometimes you wonder
, are you listening
?  If you have that special food
that I really like, then of course I'll listen
.  Do you understand what I mean
?  Okay, let's
continue.  I'll read it pretty
quickly now
.  The devil is speaking right now.  The
evil part of the mind is speaking
right now.
You should lead the person
by the hand to nothing at all
.  Teach them
nothing.  Make sure their concentration
is filled with
activity.  The masters of
meditation in my system.   Sit down
.  Cross your legs.  Don't think about
[music]
.  Who is speaking right now?  I
hope you know who is speaking.  Yes,
it is the devil speaking.
This is my meditation system.
You're laughing right now,
but back in the
day, when I was teaching my first yoga teacher
, I said, "I don't know
if I can do this yoga thing,
I don't know if I can do it
because I'm so
busy, I travel so much." And he
said,
"Oh yeah, I have a suggestion for
you.
When you go to the city, go
online, find a yoga class, and go.
In every country you're in, go to
a yoga class. There's a
beautiful story in Hong Kong.
There was a
yoga class, and the person was
speaking in
Chinese, and I said, 'Hey, I paid,
and I went in,
and it was all pregnant women, and
that's the best stretch I've ever
achieved in a
yoga class, you know?'"
Okay, but let me tell you something.
We went to so many yoga classes in
so many countries. In every country I've been to
, I went to a yoga class,
and I heard
hundreds of terrible
meditations. Hundreds. Do
n't think about it. Just let your mind
drift away.  And I was
okay with that.
And then, by chance, I
discovered how much bad
meditation is taught, and I'm
shocked. It's really
rare that someone has taught truly good
meditation.
That happened here 400 years ago.
This teacher, this great
writer, he said, by the way, that he
's the person who ended the war
from his retreat cabin.
Incidentally, he
said that even 400 years ago there was a
problem because people were simplifying
meditation so much that they were saying,
just think of nothing, think of
absolutely nothing. And that's the
devil's part here in this book.
And that's an important point. When you
form your opinion, this isn't a bad
yoga class. Incidentally, the yoga
is often good. The asana is really good
. The meditation before the asana is
really terrible. But often the
teacher is a good yoga teacher and teaches
good asana.
That's why you should still go.
You know that thing on an airplane? That little
plug. When they teach meditation,
I do the  Earplugs in, and when
the asana starts, I'll take them
out again. So, you can go, and you
can
learn, and it's an old
problem. So please listen.
In the tantric sense, in a Diamond Way
sense, which is the goal of the Diamond Way,
that you've completed the job before you
die. You don't think like that. You think
, oh, serenity isn't so
good. Who dies first? Who dies
last? We don't know. I
think it usually goes out of
order. Maybe I'm sitting here
and nobody's left. Do you understand what
I meant? We don't know who goes
first. We don't know who goes
last. And that's the way it
is. In this
Diamond Way system, you're trying to reach the goal
before you die. And that's
a
race. There's always this, there's
always this
background. Feel like, what about
this car accident that might
happen tomorrow? What about the
person? They're deceased. They
had a car accident. You  You think, oh
my goodness. And that lasts for 3
minutes. Then you think: "Oh dear, okay."
And what's for lunch?  That's how it
works
.  We are all in a race.
Diamond Way, I
understand.  With each verse, um,
I'll present you with a little bit of the Diamond Way.  It
's a race.  The purpose, the reason for
the diamond cage, is one of the most
important ideas of the diamond path: to
complete it, to finish it,
and then
relax.  If you don't die
, you're
okay.  Your death is
different from your death.  I know
where I'm going.  I know where I'll be
5 minutes later.  I've finished everything
.  The teachers are already waiting
for me.
Everything is ready.  You have to do it
.  You need to take care of it
while you still can.  You
need to take care of it.  And that is the
Diamond Way.  It's the focus on this
one life.  So, this person who tells you
that you're not meditating on anything
.  Literally kill yourself.
If they don't know how to
teach you meditation
, then you'd better go to the meditation
center.  It's not the 10 minutes
before class.  These are your
unrepeatable 10 minutes of life, which
are without circles.
In relation to goods, Barfitz,
with my company, generated
significantly more revenue from what we sold
.  How old is he, 90?
And even if he has $140 billion,
he's not in a position
to buy a few hours from someone.  Here
you get $100 million per
day.  I don't care how much it
costs.  I will take a bit of a
lifetime.  You can't
do it.  Nobody can do that.  The
person who teaches you bad
meditation will kill you.  They are
stealing precious time.  It's not a
small matter.  It's a
tragedy.  It's better if they give you
something like
a disease.  I am
somewhat, I am somewhat jealous of that
.  It is of
course not a joke.  You can't, you
shouldn't waste 10 minutes before a
yoga class.  They are not coming
back.  If meditation
is taught to you incorrectly, then it is
dangerous.  It would be like having your
arm cut off
.  So, it's really very
serious.  This is of
course a fun
debate, but actually it's
not a fun debate, he
really is the devil.
It kills the person's heart,
not just their body.  It's a
tragedy.  It's like someone
dying in a car accident.  It's terrible.
And it's just as terrible when
someone steals your time or you
waste your time.  That's the devil wondering
how fast his system
works.  Go reads that it
's too fast.
translate, but you can see the
text and then they all go to
freedom and then we'll see who's
speaking here?
The devil speaks.  Listen
.  The diamond route is the fastest
route, but it takes a very
long time.  If someone promises you something
, let me
explain it to you as an old man.  Let me learn
a little wisdom
.  So, this happened to me.  So I was sitting
next to someone on the plane.
Uh, would you like to know a secret
about the stock market?  You need to invest in this
.  They have these well-
known chips.  It's unbelievable.  You
need to invest your money in it now
.  The founder of Sony
Corporation, what was his name again?
Mr.
Marita.  That's what he said,
and it's a great book.  What
is the name of this
book?  It was made in Japan
and it's a great book and I
love it and he
said, let me tell you something.  If
someone really knows how the market is
developing, do you really think
they would tell you?
And the logic was
unbeatable: if someone knows for
sure how the stock market will
develop tomorrow, why would
that person
tell us here?  They would simply
invest their money and make money.  And he
laughed.  I am not playing
with the stock market.  I don't own any
shares.  This is the founder of Sony
Corporation.  Why?
Because it's how we play, it
's like horse racing.  It's exactly the
same.  Nobody knows where we'll go tomorrow
.  You can take all these stocks in
the world and they'll all say something
different.  And if you
knew, if they were an expert
, then they would quietly make more money
.  Why are we even talking about
this right now?  So this
person is promising you something impossible.
Listen.  I am a
tantric master.  I have a
special hat.  I have a ding ding
dinging and
a ding ding ding ding ding.  And look
at this thing.  Look at my robe
.   This
proves that I am a
tantric master.  Ding ding ding
ding
and all this ding ding ding
and I can take you there in three days
.  It's like one of those
stock market trading sessions.
Okay, you get your things and I
have to go to class.   Do
you understand what I mean?  The hat.
The hat won't get you into
butter.  Did you see me like that? Did you see me like that
?
Unfounded
promises that will lead you to enlightenment
, so much for your
enlightenment.  It's hard work,
continuous work.
You have to sit on your butt,
specifically in the retreat cabin, and
have many bad days, really JB, and
many hard times
, then you will reach the goal.
OK.
Diamond Way is not the
candy bar.  I like this next
verse.
Someone who doesn't clean their shoes, a
[ __ ], a very, very stupid person.  Who is
speaking right now?  Who would say something like that
?  The
devil.  And he speaks with this
beautiful angel, whose name is Wisdom
, who understands the pen
.  She says, he says, you're just
not moral.
She won't get angry, of course.
Of course not.  And he
says, I
have this great
capacity and you are simply a
beautiful woman.  I possess true
wisdom.  You're like a
Morob.  In English we say, you ca
n't share your shoes because you're just
stupid, that's what we say in
English.
You never say those
words.  Kitchens
meant and that's the name of the person
you are.  Is it something like a being that
is too nice?  Who is speaking right now?  Exactly.
The devil speaks.
You are more than a Turku.  You
appear once and then you're gone.
He attacks her somewhat.  He says, "Yes, you
are so beautiful. You are so wise, you
understand the pen, you live by the
pen, and then why are you never
home? Where are you all
day? Who are you with all the time
?
In English, we say, who are you with
all the time? Why don't you ever come
home?
You are so beautiful, you are so compassionate,
you are too wise, and you are never
home. Why?" What does he mean by that?
If you really understand the pen once
, it's once a month or
two minutes. He's kind of attacking her, saying that
he's a bad
person, that he's a bad woman
. She has to live with him at home
in a brain.
The devil has to live with the angel
in a person's mind all
day, and she's never
home, and she says, "Who is this person?
What's his name anyway? Where do you
even go? What do you even do
? Why are you never here? Do
you understand?
It
means people only think
about the pen once a week. The whole,
whole  Week thinking about another
person.
They say, "That's a bad
person," and "She treated me so badly,"
and then once a month you think, "
Oh, that person is coming from me." That
's what I did. She's not
home very often. You have to say, "Yes, of
course, I get it." That's how
you have to react now. I think it
's pretty
cool. So, he accuses her of
cheating on her husband. What is it? That's
living together in our heads. Wisdom
and ignorance. They're a couple in
our heads. Do you understand? It's
kind of cute, isn't it
?
Please make a nice picture to go with
this verse. Do you understand? With the
AI.
How many minutes do we have left?
There are a lot of different
spellings in this text.
Who's speaking now
? You can call him 2 Minutes
Buttershaft. 2 Minutes
Buttershaft. He has this secret
for a two-minute buttershaft. I
understand the whole world. It lies at
my feet. My meditation is,
I do it by not thinking about anything,
and then I really get to the
buttershaft in a few days.  If you
really want to make good karma,
by the way, in a
Western, it would be someone who
cheats you on your taxes, or whatever. But in
Buddhism, the devil asks you to make
the pen come from outside. That's his
job, that's his task.
If he makes you believe that the
person who attacked you
yesterday didn't come from your seed
, then he's won. If he
tries to make you believe that it exists out there on its own,
then if you
follow that, then you have a terrible
life, your whole
life, you're blinded.
You should be very jealous
because I am so
powerful and you are so weak. Who's
speaking
here? Exactly, the devil. Is it
true? It's not
true. When she's at home,
she's hitting all the time. If you
think about where the pen comes from, then
you would be patient and compassionate with
people, but you can't
remember. You're
weak, you understand?
She is
Stronger, but she's not home.
If she's never home, if she
never visits home, then she has
no time, no strength
to
show her strength. You have to learn it. You have to
learn this old student thing. If you sleep in class,
then you always have to
bob your head and nod like this.
That's the
skill on the third lip,
and the second skill
is to sleep with your eyes open
. But now it's like this,
why don't you just come
home? There
are many challenges when
you
're at home, figuring out if the person is from
me or not. Why do
n't you just come home?
If you decide the person who
hurt me is from their side
and decide that this is a bad
person,
then you have to try to
remember Buddhism. It's a
challenge.
What is schrophrenic? What does
that mean? He hurt me. He
said something bad to me, and he came from me. Wait, he
can come from me. Yes, he comes
From me. It's
not easy when you
forget all your Buddhism. Someone has
forgotten you and you say, "Oh, what
an
idiot."  He raised you that way.  What kind of
strange person is that?
Perhaps it comes from me, or no, from
some people, but not
him.  It's simple, why can't you
just leave the house
?  That's the last
word.  The beautiful lady appears.
This
means the beautiful woman represents
wisdom.  She comes back home
and says, "Hello, I'm here. Who is
this?"
She understands the pen and she uses
it.  I'm also in real life. Love.  Some people
understand the concept but never use it
in real life, and they complain
about other people all the time.   So now
she's talking to him.  We have another
minute.  Stay tuned
.  When I was sitting in the
refugee camp in Jesur and it was about
45° Celsius with rain on my head, rain was
dripping through the
roof.
Then I made a promise.
I said that in the future, if
I become a teacher
, I will make them suffer.
And now it has come true
[laughter]
.  I really did have that
thought.  It's obviously not a very
good
idea.  You still have
this disillusionment, of course, that your meditation
is so good and you think you can
sit there and
think of nothing, but only if you do
n't have good qualities, but you do
have the tools to achieve those qualities
.  In this case, it means
you don't know how to meditate
.  No one has ever
learned how to meditate.  Thinking about nothing
is a form of meditation.
So you will never be a good person
because you don't have the skills
for it.  You don't have the
toolbox that is meditation.  You
think meditation is about sitting and
not thinking.  Okay, cool.
Kuma.  Okay, we'll stop.  M.